(武市)おのおの方…｡
(似蔵)蛾は 闇を飛んでいた｡
自らの意志とは関係なく➡
万事 ぬかりのないよう
お願いいたします｡
ただ ひたすらに…｡
(似蔵)だが そのときは もう➡
(また子)心配しなくても
大丈夫っすよ！ 先輩｡
(似蔵)光を見つけた蛾は
その周りを飛び続ける｡
(つんぽ)当面は 表立って動くのは
拙者だけでござるからな｡
蛾は 光から
離れられなくなっている｡
(似蔵)闇を恐れ 光を求め➡
(似蔵)真っ暗な闇のなかを
蛾は ただ ひたすらに飛ぶ｡
♪♪～
(武市)行きましょう｡
(武市)我々の伝説の幕開けです｡
A moth flew in the darkness... The moth...
♪♪～
Did nothing but fly in complete darkness.
Scared of the dark and searching for light, it flew on...
When the moth found a light, it flew around and around it...
But...
By that time, the moth could no longer pull itself away from the light even if it wanted to.
I wish you all the best of luck.
There's no need to worry, senpai.
If anything happens, I'll be the one to deal with it.
Let's go.
It's time to...begin our legend.
[Tetsuya Murata is this episode's client. He runs a swordsmith business with his younger sister, Tetsuko.]
[His father was, Jintetsu, Edo's best swordsmith. Benizakura, his infamous creation, has gone missing...]
(似蔵)ちょいと失礼｡
Excuse me a moment.
(似蔵)
桂 小太郎殿と お見受けする｡
I'm looking for Kotaro Katsura-dono.
(桂)人違いだ…｡
(似蔵)心配いらんよ｡
You've got the wrong guy.
No need to worry.
(似蔵)ｵﾚは
幕府の犬でも何でもない｡
I'm not one of those Bakufu government dogs or anything.
(桂)犬は犬でも
血に飢えた狂犬といったところか｡
You're a dog, but more like the bloodthirsty, rabid kind.
(桂)近頃 ちまたで 辻斬りが
横行しているとは聞いていたが➡
I've heard there's been a Tsujigiri roaming the streets lately.
[Note: A Tsujigiri is someone who kills innocent people randomly in order to test a new sword or skill.]
噛みつく相手は選んだほうがいい｡
You should be careful who you try to bite.
(似蔵)ﾌﾌｯ…
あいにく ｵﾚも相棒も➡
Unfortunately, my partner and I thirst for the blood of strong men like you.
ｱﾝﾀのような つわものの血を
欲していてね｡
ひとつ やり合ってくれんかね？
Will you fight me?
(桂)ｷｻﾏ その刀！
Shit! That sword...
あらら… こんなもんかい｡
Oh, my... Is that all you've got?
["Croquette Sandwiches Are Always the Most Popular Food Sold at the Stalls"]
(野次馬)おいおい 何の騒ぎでえ？
Hey, what's all the hubbub?
(野次馬)
また死体があがったらしいよ｡
It seems another corpse popped up.
(野次馬)
なんでぇ また辻斬りかい？
Oh, that Tsujigiri again? How many people has he killed now?
(野次馬)もう これで何人目だい？
I've heard that... He only goes after ronin.
(野次馬)狙われてるのは
浪人ばかりだという話だがねぇ｡
(野次馬)これじゃあ 恐ろしくて
夜遊びもできねえや！
It's so scary that I can't go out on the town at night.
(野次馬)まっ しばらく家で
嫁さん 大事にしろってことさね｡
Well, that just means... You'll have to stay home and take care of your wife.
(笑い声)
♪♪～
(新八)お茶です！
Here's your tea.
(銀時)あの… 今日は何の用で？
Umm... What brings you here today?
♪♪～
What is this? Why has she come here? She's creepy.
何なんだよ！
何しに来たんだよ この人!!
怖えよ…｡ 黙ったままなんだけど｡
She's been silent this whole time. Is she mad?
怒ってんの？ 何か怒ってんの!?
何か ｵﾚ 悪いことした？
Is she mad about something? Did I do something bad to her?
怒ってんですか？ あれ…
笑ってんじゃないですか？
Is she angry? She's smiling, isn't she?
(神楽)新八… お前のお茶が
気に食わなかったね！
Shinpachi, she doesn't like your tea.
Our guest is a coffee person, not a tea person, uh-huh.
お客様は お茶派ではなく
ｺｰﾋｰ派だったｱﾙ｡
You're a tea server. You should be able to figure out which one she is.
お茶くみだったら
そのへん 見極めろよ！
だから お前は
新一じゃなくて 新八ｱﾙね！
That's why you're Shinpachi, not Shinichi. What is a "pachi"?
[NOTE: The "pachi" in "Shinpachi" means "eight" in Japanese. "Ichi" means "one" in Japanese.]
何だよ 八って…｡
んなもん ﾊﾟｯと見で➡
There's no way I can tell that just by looking at her!
わかるわけないだろう！
ｵﾚ すぐﾋﾟﾝときたぞ!!
I noticed it right away. Take a look at our guest.
見てみろ！ お客様
口が ｺｰﾋｰ豆みたいだろうが!!
Her mouth looks like a coffee bean.
観察力が足りねえんだよ お前は｡
You don't have very good observational skills.
ｺｰﾋｰです｡
Here's your coffee.
おい！ なんだよ
全然 変わらねえじゃねえか!!
Hey! What is that?!
Nothing's changed at all!!
銀さんだって ｺｰﾋｰ豆とか
言ってたでしょうが！
You said her mouth looked like a coffee bean!!
言ってませ～ん｡
I did not. I was talking about the side-view of a dorayaki.
[NOTE: Dorayaki is a Japanese sweet that consists of two pancake-like patties with sweet red bean paste in between.]
どら焼き 横からの図と
言ったんです！
(定春)ﾌﾜｧ～！
Really, could you cut it out already?
ちょっ… もうﾎﾝﾄ
いいかげんにしてくんない？
なんで 自分の家で こんな➡
Why does it have to be so tense in my own home?
息苦しい思いをしなきゃ
ならねえんだよ！
あの目 見てたら
吸い込まれそうなんだけど！
I feel like I'd get sucked in if I stared into those eyes.
[TEL]
あっ はいはい… 万事屋ですけど｡
Oh. Hello. This is the Odd Jobs.
新八 こうなったら最後の手段ね！
あれを出そう!!
Shinpachi, we've got to use our last resort. Let's use it.
え… いや でも
あれ 銀さんのだし 怒られるよ｡
Huh? But that's Gin-san's. He'll get mad.
いいんだよ！ ｱｲﾂも そろそろ
乳離れしなきゃいけないんだから｡
It's all right. He's got to be weaned off of it by now.
(神楽)ﾔﾂには 親がいない｡
He has no parents.
We need to raise him into...a proper adult.
私たちが 立派な大人に
育てなきゃいけないね｡
Hey, I'm going out for a bit.
おう！ ｵﾚ ちょっくら出るわ｡
あっ ちょっと
どこ行くんですか!?
Oh! Hey, where are you going?!
仕事！
お客さんの相手は頼んだぞ!!
Work. Take care of our guest.
ｳｿつけ～！
自分だけ 逃げるつもりだろう!!
Liar!! You're just trying to escape!!
(ため息)
いちご牛乳でございます！
Have some strawberry milk.
((ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ…｡
Elizabeth, samurai should eat plain and simple things.
武士は 質素で素朴なものを
食していればよい｡
If you consume strawberry milk, parfaits, and other soft and sweet foods,
いちご牛乳だ… ﾊﾟﾌｪだ…｡
甘ったれた
軟弱なものを食していたら➡
体だけじゃなく
心まで堕落してしまうぞ))
then your body as well as your heart will become corrupt.
♪♪～
(２人)おっ…｡
泣いた～！
やった～ そんなに好きなの？
It cried!! We did it!! Does she like it that much?!
(神楽)ｸﾞｯｼﾞｮﾌﾞｱﾙ！
新八 よくやったね!!
Good job. Well done, Shinpachi!
あれ… やったのか？ これ｡
Huh? Did we really do it?
(鉄矢)はぁ～っ!!
Umm... Excuse me. I'm from the Odd Jobs.
あの～ すいませ～ん｡
万事屋ですけど～｡
あの～ すいませ～ん！
Umm... Excuse me. I'm from the Odd Jobs!
すいませ～ん！
万事屋ですけど～!!
Excuse me. I'm the Odd Jobs guy!
すいませ～ん!!
万事屋ですけど～!!
Excuse me. I'm the Odd Jobs guy!
Huh?! What'd you say?!
(鉄矢)あ～ん!? あんだって～!?
万事屋ですけど～！
I'm the Odd Jobs guy! We talked on the phone!!
お電話 いただいて
まいりました～!!
I told you I don't need a newspaper!!
新聞なら いらねえ って
言ってんだろうが～!!
ﾊﾞｰｶ ﾊﾞｰｶ ｳﾝｺ！
どうせ 聞こえねえだろ｡ どわっ！
Stupid, stupid piece of crap! You can't hear me anyway.
いや～！
たいへん すまぬことをした～!!
I've done a terrible thing!!
(鉄矢)こちらも 汗だくで
仕事を しているゆえ➡
I'm all sweaty from working, so my hand slipped. I'm sorry!
手が 滑ってしまった～！
申し訳ない!!
いえいえ…｡
It's all right.
They definitely heard me.
ぜってえ 聞こえてたよ ｺｲﾂら…｡
I haven't told you yet...
(鉄矢)申し遅れた～！
あん？
We siblings are swordsmiths!
私たちは 兄妹で
刀鍛冶を営んでおります！
I'm Tetsuya, the older brother!
私は 兄の鉄矢！
そして こっちは…!!
And this is...
Hey, at least greet him, Tetsuko!
(鉄矢)って お～い!!
挨拶くらいせぬか 鉄子～!!
(鉄矢)名のらねば 坂田さん
お前を なんと呼んでいいか➡
If you don't say your name, Sakata-san won't know what to call you, Tetsuko!!
わからぬだろう！ 鉄子～!!
Big Brother, you already told him my name. And loudly.
おにいさ～ん
もう 言っちゃってるから｡
でかい声で 言っちゃってるから｡
(鉄矢)すいません 坂田さん！
Sorry, Sakata-san, she's a shy beast!
(鉄矢)ｺｲﾂ ｼｬｲな
あんちきしょうなもんで～！
Anyway, it must be pretty tough being a sword smith when swords have been outlawed.
それにしても 廃刀令の ご時勢に
刀鍛冶とは➡
いろいろ 大変そうですね～｡
でね～！
Anyway, the job I want you to do is...
今回 貴殿に
頼みたい仕事というのは～!!
お～い 無視か おい！
聞こえてなかったのかなぁ？
Hey, you're ignoring me? Maybe he didn't hear me...
Actually, someone stole Benizakura, the masterpiece
実は 先代の…！
つまり 私の父ですが➡
that the late head...in other words, my father, created!
彼が作り上げた傑作 紅桜が
何者かに盗まれましてな～！
Oh?! And what is Benizakura?
おぉ～ 紅桜とは
いったい なんですか？
これを 貴殿に
探し出してきてもらいたい！
I want you to find it.
あれ～!?
まだ 聞こえてないの～!?
What?! He can't hear me again?!
(鉄矢)紅桜は 江戸いちばんの
刀匠 と うたわれた➡
Benizakura is a sword forged by my father, Jintetsu,
親父の仁鉄が うった刀で➡
who was considered the greatest swordsmith in Edo.
そのなかでも
最高傑作といわれる 業物！
It was said to be his greatest creation.
Its blade could split boulders and gleams pale crimson in the moonlight.
鋭き刃は 岩をも切り裂き➡
月明かりに照らすと
淡い紅色を帯びる｡
It's as mysterious and beautiful as cherry blossoms at night.
その刀身は
夜桜の如く 妖しく美しい！
A truly splendid sword that has no equal.
まさに ふたつとない名刀!!
そうですか～！ すごいっすね～!!
Is that so?! That's amazing!
で 犯人に
心当たりは ないんですか～！
So do you have any idea who stole it?
But the Benizakura is a thing no human should ever touch.
しか～し!! 紅桜は 決して➡
人が触れていい 代物ではない！
おにいさ～ん！ 人の話 聞こう！
Sir?! Listen to what other people have to say!!
どこ見てる？
ｵﾚのこと 見てる～!?
Where are you looking? Are you looking at me?!
It all started when my father mysteriously died one month after forging the Benizakura.
(鉄矢)なぜなら！
紅桜を うった父が➡
１か月後に
ぽっくり死んだのを 皮切りに➡
それ以降も 紅桜に関わる人間は➡
Ever since then, misfortune has befallen
必ず 凶事に 見舞われた！
everyone who became involved with the Benizakura!
あれは… あれは 人の魂を吸う
妖刀なのだ～!!
It's... It's a demon sword that consumes people's souls!
おいおい！
ちょっと 勘弁してくださいよ～！
Come on. Give me a break. That means misfortune might fall on me too!!
じゃあ ｵﾚにも
何か 不吉なことが➡
起こるかもしれないじゃ
ないですか～!!
(鉄矢)坂田さん!!
Sakata-san.
Please find the Benizakura before it causes any more tragedy!
紅桜が 災いを呼び起こす前に➡
何とぞ よろしくお願いしま～す!!
Listen to me!! He hasn't heard a single thing I've said!!
聞けや～!! ｺｲﾂ ﾎﾝﾄ 会ってから➡
１回も ｵﾚの話 聞いてねえよ！
(鉄子)兄者と話すときは…｡
んっ？
When you talk to my brother...
You've got to get close to his ear and speak from your diaphragm.
もっと 耳もとに近寄って➡
腹から 声を出さんと…｡
えっ？ そうなの？
Huh? Really?!
Sir!! Excuse me!!
おにいさ～ん!! あの～!!
Shut up!!
うるさ～い!!
ぶべら～!!
So you're saying you found that here?
じゃあ ここで
見つけたっていうの？ それ｡
血染めの 所持品…｡
That bloody thing.
おまけに ここ数日
桂さんの姿を 見てないなんて…｡
Furthermore, you haven't seen Katsura-san for several days?
Why didn't you tell us about this earlier, Elizabeth?
どうして もっと早く
言わなかったんだ ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ！
[A Tsujigiri has been roaming the streets lately... Do you suppose that...]
Elizabeth, you know better than anyone
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ！
ｷﾐが いちばん わかってるだろ！
桂さんは
そのへんの 辻斬りなんかに➡
that Katsura-san isn't the sort of person who would lose to some Tsujigiri.
負ける人じゃない！
(神楽)でも これを見るかぎり➡
But looking at this, it's obvious something happened to him.
何か あったことは 明白｡
早く 見つけ出さないと
大変なことになるかも…｡
If we don't find him quickly, something terrible might happen.
桂さん… んっ？
Katsura-san...
[It may already be too late...]
ﾊﾞｶ野郎～!!
You idiot!!
[Gah!!]
If you don't believe in Katsura-san, then who will?!
お前が 信じないで
誰が 桂さんを信じるんだ～!!
When you were captured by that evil magistrate,
お前が 前に
悪徳奉行に 捕まったときはな➡
桂さんは どんなになっても
あきらめなかったぞ～!!
Katsura-san never gave up on you, no matter what!
今 お前に できることは なんだ！
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ!!
Right now, what is it you must do, Elizabeth?!
桂さんのために できることは
なんだ～!!
What must you do for Katsura-san?!
言ってみろ！
言え！ 言うんだ～!!
Tell me!!
Say it! Say it!!
(ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ)痛えなぁ…｡
うっ…｡
That hurts.
That hurts. Let go of me. Or I'll rip your guts out.
痛えな｡ 離せよ！ ﾐﾝﾁにすんぞ｡
すいませ～ん!!
Sorry!!
Shinpachi, I'm going to look around with Sadaharu.
新八 私は 定春と
いろいろ探してみるｱﾙ｡
(神楽)お前は ｴﾘｰと一緒に
辻斬りのほうを調べるｱﾙ！
You look for the Tsujigiri with Lizzie!!
ｱﾊﾊ…｡
♪♪～
[Recycled Goods Shop
Earth Defense Army Base]
A demon sword? There's no way there'd be one in a recycle shop.
(十徳の娘)妖刀？ そんなもん
ﾘｻｲｸﾙｼｮｯﾌﾟに あるわけないだろう｡
Well, nowadays you can buy demon swords by mail order.
いやいや… 通販で
妖刀 買える時代だからなぁ｡
(娘)ｱﾝﾀのは
それ 紛いもんだろう？
Those are knockoffs.
I've been to numerous pawnshops, but it's nowhere to be found.
いろいろ 質屋まわったが
どこにも なくてなぁ…｡
てっきり 売り飛ばされてると
思ったんだが…➡
I thought the thief would sell it.
But if money isn't what he was after, that means...
金目当てじゃねえってことは…｡
ｱﾝﾀの探してる その 妖刀って
ﾔﾂかどうかは 知らないけどね➡
I don't know if this is the same demon sword you're looking for,
おもしろい刀のｳﾜｻは 耳にしたよ｡
but I've heard rumors of a strange sword.
(娘)近頃 ここいらで➡
You know there's been a Tsujigiri roaming the area lately, right?
辻斬りが 流行ってるのは
知ってるかい？
Well, everyone who's met him has been killed,
(娘)ま… 出会ったﾔﾂは みんな➡
斬られちまってんだが… 遠目で➡
but there was a guy who saw him from a distance.
見たﾔﾂがいるらしくてね｡
He said the sword the slayer wielded was more like a living thing than a sword.
(娘)ｿｲﾂの持っている刀が➡
刀というより生き物
みたいだったって…｡
(娘)まっ… ｱﾝﾀも
辻斬りには気をつけなよ｡
Well, you should be careful of that Tsujigiri, too.
♪♪～
Kawakami-dono, we'll be arriving soon.
(浪士)河上殿 まもなく
目的地へ到着いたします｡
Bansai-dono, we'll be arriving soon!!
万斎殿！ そろそろ
到着なんですけど!!
(浪士)そろそろ到着でございます｡
We'll be arriving soon! Can you hear me?!
(浪士)聞こえてますか!?
(つんぽ)あぁ 了解でござるよ…｡
Okay. Got it...
[Otsu's New Album "Your Father is a XX"]
Now then...
さてと… 拙者の口八丁で➡
I wonder if my smooth-talking can win them over...
うまくﾔﾂらを転がすことが
できるでござるかな…｡
(つんぽ)一世一代の
大ﾌﾟﾛﾃﾞｭｰｽで ござる｡
This is a once-in-a-lifetime production.
[Sake]
[Defeat the Tsujigiri]
ちゃーっす！ ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ先輩｡
Greetings!!
[Note: Yakisoba is a sort of fried noodles.]
Elizabeth-senpai, I bought you some yakisoba buns!
焼きそばﾊﾟﾝ 買ってきました｡
[I asked for a croquette sandwich.]
They were sold out, so I got you the closest thing I could find.
いや ｺﾛｯｹﾊﾟﾝ売り切れていたんで➡
似たようなﾔﾂ 買ってきました｡
Sorry.
すみませんっす｡
How's it going? Has the Tsujigiri shown up?
どうっすか 辻斬り
のﾔﾂは来ましたか？
でもやっぱり ﾑﾁｬ
じゃないっすかね｡
But don't you think it's a little reckless to ask the Tsujigiri in person about Katsura-san?
辻斬りに 直接 桂さんのこと➡
聞くなんて まだ犯人が辻斬り
って 決まったわけじゃないし｡
We're not even sure if he's the culprit.
うわぁっ！
Hey, what are you doing?!
何すんですか!? ちょっと｡
[Eligo 13 (on headband)]
[Note: Parody of the manga series Golgo 13. Elizabeth + Golgo 13]
[Don't stand behind me.]
Shut up! I can't even tell which side of you is the front or the back!
うるさいよ… どっちが➡
前だか 後ろだか
わからん体してるくせに｡
(岡っ引き)おい｡
Hey.
何やってんだ ｷｻﾏら｡
What are you doing here?
こんなところで… 怪しいﾔﾂらめ｡
You're kind of suspicious.
なんだ… 奉行所の人か｡
Oh... It's a policeman from the magistrate. Don't scare me like that.
びっくりさせないでくださいよ｡
(岡っ引き)
びっくりしたじゃないよ｡
Don't give me that. I'm asking you what you're doing.
(岡っ引き)
何やってんだって聞いてんの｡
[We don't need to tell you!]
Don't you two understand?
(岡っ引き)お前ら わかってんの!?
Lately, there's been...
最近 ここいらにはな…｡
(似蔵)辻斬りが出るから危ないよ｡
A Tsujigiri in the area. It's very dangerous.
はっ… うわぁっ！
《ｴﾘｻﾞ… ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ!!》
Eliza...
Elizabeth!!
Come on. I came here looking for a demon sword...
おいおい… 妖刀 捜して
こんなところまで来てみりゃ➡
どっかで見たﾂﾗじゃねえか｡
Only to come across some familiar faces.
G-Gin-san!!
ぎ… 銀さん｡
(似蔵)ﾎﾝﾄだ｡
It's true.
どこかで嗅いだにおいだね｡
I've smelled that scent of yours before.
♪♪～
Y-You're... Butcher...
あっ ｱﾝﾀは… 人斬り｡
人斬り似蔵！
Nizo the Butcher!!
So you were behind those slayings!!
件の辻斬りは…
ｱﾝﾀの仕業だったのか｡
それに銀さんも… なんでここに!?
Gin-san, why are you here?!
目的は違えど➡
Our objectives were different,
ｱｲﾂに 用があるのは
一緒らしいよ 新八君｡
but it seems we were looking for the same guy.
Shinpachi-kun.
嬉しいねぇ… わざわざｵﾚに
会いに来てくれたってわけだ｡
I'm pleased. You came all this way to see me.
(似蔵)ｺｲﾂは 災いを呼ぶ妖刀➡
I heard this was a cursed demon sword that brings misfortune,
と聞いていたがね どうやら➡
but it seems to attract the strong too.
つわものを引き寄せるらしい｡
It allowed me to meet you and Katsura,
(似蔵)桂にｱﾝﾀ…｡
(似蔵)こうも会いたい
ﾔﾂに会わせてくれるとは➡
exactly the people I wanted to see.
ｵﾚにとっては 吉兆を
呼ぶ 刀かもしれん…｡
Maybe it's a sword of good-fortune for me.
桂さん!? 桂さんを
どうしたんだ お前｡
Katsura-san?!
What did you do to Katsura-san?!
My, my. He was an acquaintance of yours?
(似蔵)おやおや… おたくらの
知り合いだったのかい それは➡
Sorry about that.
すまんことをした… ｵﾚも
おﾆｭｰの刀を 手に入れて➡
I was playing around with my new sword and I ended up killing him.
はしゃいでいたものでね
ついつい斬っちまった…｡
Zura would never lose to a low rent cutthroat like you.
ﾂﾞﾗが ﾃﾒｴみてえな ただの
人殺しに負けるわけねえだろ｡
Don't get angry. I apologize for that.
怒るなよ 悪かったと言っている｡
あ… そうだ｡
Oh yeah.
ほら… せめてﾔﾂの
形見だけでも返すよ｡
Here. At the very least, I'll give you a memento of him.
I cut it off of him as a trophy, but I'm sure he'd want you to have it.
記念にと むしり
とってきたんだが➡
ｱﾝﾀらが 持ってたほうが
ﾔﾂも喜ぶだろう… しかし➡
But is Katsura really a man?
桂ってのは 本当に男かい？
この なめらかな髪
まるで女のような…｡
This smooth hair is as silky and soft as a woman's.
何度も 同じこと
言わせんじゃねえよ｡
Don't make me repeat myself.
ﾂﾞﾗは ﾃﾒｴみてえな ｻﾞｺに➡
Zura would never lose against a small fry like you.
やられるようなﾔﾂじゃねえんだよ｡
ｸｸ… 確かに｡
Indeed. I'm no match for him.
ｵﾚならば かなうまいよ｡
But I wasn't the one who killed him.
(似蔵)だが… ﾔﾂを
斬ったのはｵﾚじゃない｡
I just let it use my body for a bit.
(似蔵)ｵﾚは ちょいと
体を 貸しただけでね｡
(似蔵)なぁ 紅桜よ｡
Right, Benizakura?
ｺｲﾂは…｡
T-This is...
ｸﾝｸﾝ ｸﾝｸﾝ…｡
(神楽)すっかり
暗くなってしまったｱﾙ｡
It's gotten really dark.
(神楽)定春… もう帰らないと➡
Sadaharu, if we don't go soon home, Gin-chan and Shinpachi will worry about us.
銀ちゃんたちが心配する｡
…わけないか｡
Or not.
(神楽)ﾂﾞﾗなら きっと大丈夫ｱﾙ｡
I think Zura will be okay. There's no way he'd die so easily.
(神楽)ｱｲﾂが ちょっとや
そっとで 死ぬわけないｱﾙ｡
今日は いったん帰って➡
Let's go home for today and look for him tomorrow.
明日 また捜しに来るｱﾙ…｡
(神楽)定春!?
Sadaharu?
Sadaharu, have you picked up Zura's scent here?
定春 ここからﾂﾞﾗの
においがするｱﾙか？
ﾜﾝ！
♪♪～
なんだろ？ あの船｡
What is that boat?
Hey.
(浪士)おい｡
Did you find him?
(浪士)どうだ 見つかったか？
It's no good. Okada-san's got that illness again... He's been real quiet...
(浪士)ﾀﾞﾒだ… こりゃ また
例の病気が出たな 岡田さん｡
Ever since he was defeated by some ronin, too.
どこかの浪人にやられてから➡
しばらく
おとなしかったってのに｡
(浪人)やっぱ危ねえよ あの人｡
He's really dangerous.
こないだも あの桂を斬ったとか
触れ回っていたが➡
He was bragging that he defeated Katsura. I wouldn't put it past him.
あの人なら やりかねんよ｡
What are we going to do?
どうすんだ！ お前らが
ちゃんと見張っとかねえから!!
This happened because you weren't keeping watch over him.
あれの存在が 明るみに出たら…｡
If the existence of that thing ever came to light...
とりあえず 船に戻って出直そう｡
Anyway, let's go back to the ship and start over.
(神楽)定春 お前は これを
銀ちゃんたちの所へ届けるｱﾙ｡
Sadaharu, take this to Gin-chan and the others.
(定春)ﾜﾝ！
Even if you see a cute lady dog, don't take any detours.
かわいい ﾒｽ犬がいても
寄り道しちゃﾀﾞﾒだよ！
上にのっかっちゃ ﾀﾞﾒだよ～！
And don't climb on top of them!
All right. I'm off.
よし いくか！
♪♪～
ﾌｯﾌｯﾌ…｡
ぐぅぅ！
ああっ！
くっ!!
♪♪～
わあっ！
Gin-san!
銀さんっ！
[What a violent development. Did this turn into a different anime?]
♪♪～
あ…！
そこっ！
There!
♪♪～
That's odd.
(似蔵)おかしいねぇ おい｡
ｱﾝﾀ もっと強くなかったかい？
I thought you were stronger than that.
おかしいねぇ おい｡
That's odd.
ｱﾝﾀ それ ﾎﾝﾄに刀ですか？
Is that thing really a sword?
刀というより
生き物みたいだったって…？
It's more like a living thing than a sword.
冗談じゃねえよ！
You've got to be kidding.
ありゃ生き物ってより…➡
That's not a living thing...
化け物じゃねえか!!
It's more like a monster!!
銀さ～ん！
Gin-san!!
んっ？
ｸｯ…！
ううっ！
ｹﾝｶは剣だけで
やるもんじゃねえんだよ！
Fights aren't only won with swords!
ﾌﾌｯ…｡
What?!
なに!?
ああっ！
This isn't a fight.
ｹﾝｶじゃない…｡
It's a battle to the death.
殺し合いだろうよ｡
♪♪～
ああっ！
銀さ～ん！
Gin-san!!
《野郎…｡
Is he an alien or something?
着ぐるみでも
着てんじゃねえのか？
This strength isn't human.
人間の力じゃねえ… あっ！》
Hey, this is bad...
おいおい こりゃ やべえ…｡
《ｳｿ… ｳｿだ｡
No way. This can't be. Gin-san is...
銀さんが… 銀さんが…｡
Gin-san is... Gin-san is...
銀さんが！ …銀さん!!》
Gin-san!!
(似蔵)後悔しているかい？
Do you regret not killing me in our last battle?
以前 ｵﾚとやり合ったとき
なぜ殺しておかなかったと…｡
If you had killed me, this wouldn't have happened to you and Katsura.
ｵﾚを殺しておけば 桂もｱﾝﾀも
こんな目には遭わなかった｡
This all came to pass because of your naivety.
すべては
ｱﾝﾀの甘さが招いた結果だ｡
(似蔵)白夜叉…｡
The White Knight.
(似蔵)あの人も さぞや
がっかりしてるだろうよ｡
He's probably really disappointed.
かつて 共に戦った盟友たちが
揃いも揃って このｻﾞﾏだ｡
That all the old comrades he fought beside ended up like this.
(似蔵)ｱﾝﾀたちのような
弱い侍のために➡
This country turned corrupt because of weak samurai like you.
この国は腐敗した｡
If I had been by his side instead of you, this would still be the Japan of old.
ｱﾝﾀではなく
ｵﾚが あの人の隣にいれば➡
この国は
こんな有様には ならなかった！
士道だ節義だ…
くだらんものは 侍には必要ない｡
Samurai don't need silly things like a warrior code or morals.
侍に必要なのは 剣のみさね｡
Samurai only need swords.
Your sword is broken. You're no longer a samurai.
剣の折れた ｱﾝﾀたちは
もう侍じゃないよ｡
惰弱な 侍は➡
Weak samurai should vanish from this country.
この国から消えるがいい… んっ？
剣が折れたって？
My sword is broken?
剣なら まだあるぜ｡
I still have a sword. One more sword, just in case.
とっておきのが もう１本！
《抜けな…》
I can't pull it out...
だぁぁぁ!!
Oh, my. You took off my arm. You're really awful.
(似蔵)あらら
腕が取れちまったよ｡
ひどいことするね ﾎﾞｸ｡
それ以上 きてみろ！
次は左手をもらう!!
Don't come any closer! Or I'll make it a set!
(笛)
Hey! What's going on down there?!
(岡っ引き)おい！
そこで何をやっている!!
Tsk. Such annoyances. We'll finish this later.
(似蔵)ﾁｯ…
うるさいのが来ちまった｡
勝負は おあずけだな｡
Let's meet again when we have the chance.
まぁ また機会があったら
やり合おうや｡
(岡っ引き)おいっ 待て!!
Hey, wait!!
あ… ﾊｯ！
銀さん！ しっかりしてください
銀さん!!
Gin-san! Hang on! Gin-san!
ﾍﾍｯ… 新八｡
Shinpachi, I knew you had it in you.
ｵﾒｴは やればできる子だと
思ってたよ｡
Gin-san!
銀さん… 銀さ～ん!!
Gin-san!!
Hey!
おい！ お前 この船の船員ｱﾙか？
Are you a part of this ship's crew?
ちょいと中 案内してもらおうか
頭ﾌﾞﾁ抜かれたくなかったらな｡
Could you show me around? Unless you want me make your head go pop.
おい 聞いてんのか!?
Hey, you hear me?
あ…！
[Danger approaches...]
[Kagura.]
[Shinpachi goes after...]
[The truth.]
[What is the Benzakura?!]
[Next Episode: "Be Careful Not to Leave Your Umbrella Somewhere"]
[Shinsuke Takasugi shows up in Edo once again. What does he plan to use the cybersword, Benizakura, for?]
[Is Katsura really dead?! And what will the badly injured Gintoki do?!]